PRADNESH SANDERAN

COMPUTER SCIENCE STUDENT

Profile

Self-assured computer science student and team leader with diverse experience utilizing programming languages for assignments and projects and fluid understanding of object oriented programming languages(Java) and functional programming languages (Haskell) . Highly trained in various technology environments.

Experience

TEACHER

Rumah Hope, Kuala Lumpur | 2018 - 2019

I volunteered as a teacher at the Rumah Hope Children's Home in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. Here, I taught the children, whose ages ranged from 4 to 16 years old, science and English every Friday for the years 2018 and 2019

VOLUNTEERED AT THE ANIMAL SHELTER

SPCA Kajang, Kuala Lumpur - 2016

I volunteered at the SPCA where i had cleaned the cages and kennels of the dogs and cats. I had also given the dogs a bath and fed them

CO-FOUNDER OF A SOUP KITCHEN

Indrani's Kitchen, Kuala Lumpur | 2013 - Present

In 2013, me and 4 others co-founded a soup kitchen called Indrani's Kadai where on the first Saturday of every month we would hand out food to the homeless around the Kuala Lumpur City Centre

Education

BSC COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh | 2019 - 2023

This degree is focused on understanding, designing, implementing and using computing systems, ranging in scale and complexity from the tiny components of a single processor to the globe-spanning internet. It also concerns the practical techniques of programming computers to solve real and difficult problems with links to other subjects, from electronics, physics, mathematics and various others

A-LEVLES

HELP Academy, Kuala Lumpur | 2018 - 2019 4A

Personal information

Gender

Male

Residence

11/4 New Arthur Place, Edinburgh, Scotland

Nationality

Malaysian

Achievements



A LEVELS

4A

SCHOOL LEAVING CERTIFICATE (SPM)

7A+ 2A 1B+

Skills

Programming Languages

Java Haskell Python React Android Studio



Languages

English Malay Language Tamil



Professional Skills

Effective multitasker with outstanding organizational and customer service skills Excellent team building skills, meeting preparation and organization Event management

skills







CO-FOUNDER OF A SOUP KITCHEN

Indranis Kitchen | 2013 - Present

TEACHER AT A CHILDREN'S HOME

Rumah Hope | 2018 - 2019

VOLUNTEERED AT THE ANIMAL SHELTER

SPCA Kajang - 2016

PACKED FOOD FOR TYPHOON VICTIMS

Stop Hunger Now - 2014

I had helped pack food packets for the victims of typhoon rammasun in Philippines with Stop Hunger Now

Projects

2020 **STUDENT STUDY ASSISTANT**

Hello World Hackathon

During the Hello World Hackathon, me and my team built a program that would help people study. if a student uploads a picture of their textbook or any notes to the program, the programs scans the image for keywords that would be related to what the student is studying based on its library. it then does web scrapping to find the most relevant information about that topic from various sources such as wikipedia, google scholar and youtube. it then returns the information to a webpage. the information can then be synthesized and converted to audio. This would help students as it reduces the time spent looking up information as the most relevant information is handed to them. it also helps the visually impaired as the can listen to the audio once the text is synthesized.

2020 INSIGHT

Hack The Burgh

Android application written in native Java. This application curates the most sustainable recreational activities that tourists can get in their vicinity, even considering the weather! We aim to make this the only app tourists will ever need. When travellers first come to an unknown city, they probably won't be that familiar with the local weather which might potentially affect their travel plan, so our app can detect the climate based on three indexes: weather, temperature and wind speed to recommend the suitable attractions (categorized as indoor and outdoor) for travellers to visit.

Contact

Contact

- A Edinburgh, United Kingdom
- **** 07367871017

Social

- in linkedin.com/in/pradnesh-sanderan-70b24b19a
- https://github.com/pradneshsanderan
- https://pradneshsanderan.github.io/pradneshsanderan/

Interests

- Programming
- Photography
- Software Development
- Robotics
- Squash
- Football